THE FOLLOWING TAKES PLACE BETWEEN SIX A.M. AND SEVEN A.M.
AMERICA HAS BEEN VICTIMIZED AGAIN.
LAST NIGHT'S TERRORIST ATTACK IN SAN ANTONIO IS NOW THE LATEST IN THIS SERIES OF BOMBINGS...
THAT BEGAN ELEVEN WEEKS AGO IN TEN DIFFERENT CITIES.
OVER NINE HUNDRED PEOPLE HAVE BEEN KILLED THUS FAR.
AND WHILE NO ONE IS CLAIMING RESPONSIBILITY FOR THIS WAVE OF DEATH,
EVIDENCE POINTS TO ISLAMIC MILITANTS.
HERE IN LOS ANGELES, THE MOOD CAN ONLY BE DESCRIBED AS TENSE AND FEARFUL...
AS THE DEPARTMENT OF HOMELAND SECURITY IS URGING ALL CITIZENS...
TO REPORT, WITHOUT DELAY, ANY SUSPICIOUS PERSONS OR ACTIVITIES.
WE SPOKE WITH A DEPARTMENT SPOKESPERSON WHO SAYS, QUOTE,
WE DON'T WANT TO START A WITCH HUNT,
BUT WE WOULD RATHER ERR ON THE SIDE OF CAUTION THAN BECOME THE NEXT TARGET.
HE THEN WENT ON TO SAY THAT THE VIGILANCE OF THE PUBLIC...
IS OUR BEST LINE OF DEFENSE AGAINST ATTACK.
HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY!
HEY! STOP! STOP! STOP! OPEN THE DOORS!
PLEASE. I HAVE TO GET TO WORK.
I'LL BE LATE FOR WORK. PLEASE, OPEN THE DOOR.
COME ON, MAN. OPEN THE DOOR.
OPEN THE DOOR! I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU!
I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU DIDN'T OPEN THE DOOR!
I HAVE AS MUCH RIGHT TO BE ON THE BUS AS YOU!
OUR COUNTRY IS UNDER SIEGE.
NOW, YOU'RE THE NATIONAL SECURITY ADVISER, KAREN.
FRANKLY, I'M SURPRISED BY YOUR RESISTANCE.
THESE PLACES THAT YOU KEEP BUILDING...
THEY'RE NOTHING MORE THAN CONCENTRATION CAMPS. DETENTION FACILITIES.
AND THE CRITERIA FOR DETERMINING WHO SHALL BE DETAINED ARE VERY REASONABLE.
REASONABLE? THIS REVISED PLAN OF YOURS...
JUSTIFIES LOCKING UP EVERY AMERICAN WHO PRAYS TOWARDS MECCA.
THAT'S A RIDICULOUS EXAGGERATION, AND YOU KNOW IT.
RIGHT NOW, THE AMERICAN MUSLIM COMMUNITY IS OUR GREATEST ASSET.
THEY HAVE PROVIDED LAW ENFORCEMENT WITH HUNDREDS OF TIPS,
AND NOT A SINGLE MEMBER OF THAT COMMUNITY HAS BEEN IMPLICATED IN THESE ATTACKS.
SO FAR. MISTER PRESIDENT,
THE PEOPLE ARE LOSING FAITH IN OUR ABILITY TO PROTECT THEM.
WE'VE GOT TO DO SOMETHING ABOUT THIS NOW.
AND LOCKING UP MORE MUSLIMS WILL NOT MAKE THEM SAFER.
NO, KAREN, BUT IT WILL MAKE THEM FEEL SAFER.
WHAT ABOUT THE COST OF THE CIVIL UNREST THAT YOUR PLAN WILL CREATE?
THERE WILL BE RIOTS, DEMONSTRATIONS... SECURITY HAS ITS PRICE.
SO DOES FREEDOM, TOM.
LISTEN, I JUST DON'T SEE HOW I CAN SIGN OFF ON SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
I MEAN, WASN'T IT JUST THREE MONTHS AGO...
THAT I TOOK AN OATH TO PRESERVE, PROTECT AND DEFEND THE CONSTITUTION?
AND WHAT ABOUT PRESERVING, PROTECTING AND DEFENDING THE AMERICAN PEOPLE?
ALL OF THESE MEASURES ARE LEGAL.
BLAKE HAS BEEN ALL OVER THIS THING WITH THE ATTORNEY GENERAL.
THERE IS A PRECEDENT, SIR, ESPECIALLY IN WARTIME.
LINCOLN SUSPENDED HABEAS CORPUS. ROOSEVELT SIGNED EXECUTIVE ORDER...
YES, BLAKE, I KNOW THIS. AND ROOSEVELT IMPRISONED OVER 200,000 JAPANESE-AMERICANS...
IN WHAT MOST HISTORIANS CONSIDER TO BE A SHAMEFUL MISTAKE.
WELL, I WOULD ASK THOSE HISTORIANS HOW MANY OF THOSE JAPANESE-AMERICANS...
WERE THUS PREVENTED FROM PERPETRATING ACTS OF SABOTAGE IN THIS COUNTRY.
I REALIZE THAT WHAT I'M PROPOSING HAS ITS CHALLENGES,
BUT WE CANNOT CONTINUE TO KEEP OUR HEADS BURIED IN THE SAND.
MISTER PRESIDENT. YEAH?
- ANOTHER ATTACK? - LOS ANGELES. A BUS.
- HOW MANY CASUALTIES? - TWENTY-THREE SO FAR, INCLUDING THE SUICIDE BOMBER.
AND WE'RE STILL CERTAIN THIS MAN ASSAD IS BEHIND ALL THESE ATTACKS, RIGHT?
YES, SIR. WE CONFIRMED HE ARRIVED IN THE UNITED STATES...
THREE DAYS BEFORE THE FIRST BOMBING IN SAN ANTONIO.
AND LET US NOT FORGET, ASSAD HAS BEEN CALLING...
FOR THE DESTRUCTION OF THE UNITED STATES FOR THE LAST TWENTY YEARS.
MISTER PRESIDENT, MY ANALYSTS BELIEVE THAT ASSAD'S ORGANIZATION...
CANNOT SURVIVE WITHOUT HIM, AND ONCE HE'S DEAD, THESE ATTACKS WILL STOP.
SO THIS ASSUMES THE SUCCESS OF THE OPERATION TO TERMINATE ASSAD?
C.T.U. ESTIMATES SUCCESSFUL PROBABILITY AT SEVENTY FIVE PERCENT.
OH, I THINK THAT'S VERY GENEROUS.
YOU KNOW, IT... IT... IT SOUNDS TO ME LIKE YOU'RE ANTICIPATING FAILURE, TOM.
I FULLY ACKNOWLEDGE, SIR, THAT THIS IS OUR ONLY OPTION,
BUT I AM FERVENTLY ADVOCATING CONTINGENCIES.
CONTINGENCIES ARE WELL AND GOOD, TOM.
BUT C.T.U. NEEDS TO ELIMINATE ASSAD. THAT'S ALL THERE IS TO IT.
GOD KNOWS WE'RE PAYING A STEEP ENOUGH PRICE TO GET HIM.
I'VE TOLD YOU TWENTY TIMES, YOU DON'T SEND OUT A REPORT WITHOUT A CERTIFIED HEADER ON IT.
WELL, THIS MAKES TWENTY ONE. YOU SHOULD UPDATE YOUR COUNT.
DO YOU... AND I'M JUST CURIOUS...
EVER OPEN YOUR MOUTH WITHOUT SARCASM JUST SPILLING OUT OF IT?
SORRY, ARE WE DONE HERE? LOOK, I'M JUST TELLING YOU TO BE CAREFUL.
OTHERWISE YOU WILL FIND YOURSELF BACK SELLING LADIES SHOES IN BEVERLY HILLS.
YOU'RE REALLY SETTLING WELL INTO THE WHOLE MIDDLE-MANAGEMENT THING, AREN'T YOU?
WHAT'S YOUR PROBLEM WITH ME? I LIKED YOU FINE AS AN ANALYST.
ACTUALLY YOU WERE VERY GOOD. AS A BOSS, BIT OF A BORE.
RIGHT.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
TALK TO YOUR BOYFRIEND. THE GUY'S ON SELF-DESTRUCT.
YOU PROMISED ME YOU'D GET ALONG WITH MILO.
I'M SORRY, DARLING. THAT'S A PROMISE I JUST CAN'T KEEP.
MORRIS. MORRIS.
YOU KNOW, I HAD THE SAME PROBLEM WITH DEPARTMENT HEADS...
WHEN I FIRST STARTED, AND I LEARNED HOW TO FIT IN.
THERE'S NO REASON WHY YOU CAN'T. EXCEPT I DON'T HAPPEN TO BE A PRETTY LADY.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT? YOU'RE A HOTTIE.
NO, I'M NOT. YES, YOU ARE. DEAL WITH IT.
MORRIS, WE'RE AT WORK. SO?
IT'S UNPROFESSIONAL. ARE YOU SAYING YOU DON'T LIKE IT?
NO, I'M NOT SAYING THAT. I JUST CAME TO SEE IF YOU GOT A REQUEST FROM HOMELAND...
ON THE PRIORITY CHANNEL. NO.
WELL, WHY DID THEY SEND IT ONLY TO ME?
I DON'T KNOW. JUST TRY TO GET ALONG.
BECAUSE YOU ASKED, I WILL.
NADIA, I JUST GOT A WEIRD REQUEST FROM HOMELAND SECURITY.
THEY WANT TO SET UP A CHANNEL, AND I WANTED TO CLEAR WITH YOU FIRST.
- CONSIDER YOURSELF CLEARED. - THEY WANT IT FORMATTED ACCORDING TO MILITARY SPECS.
COORDINATING AN ASSAULT WITH THE COBRA ATTACK HELICOPTERS FROM CAMP PENDLETON.
WHEN? THIRTY MINUTES.
- AN ASSAULT ON WHO? - ASSAD.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT? WE DON'T EVEN KNOW WHERE ASSAD IS.
WE WILL. WE HAVE A LEAD. NO, WE DON'T. IF WE DID, I WOULD KNOW ABOUT IT.
WE FOUND A WAY TO GET ASSAD'S LOCATION.
HOW?
JACK BAUER. JACK'S IN A CHINESE PRISON.
NOT ANYMORE. THE PRESIDENT NEGOTIATED HIS RELEASE TWO DAYS AGO.
JACK'S COMING BACK? YES.
WELL, WHY DID THE CHINESE LET HIM GO? WHY TODAY?
DOES THIS HAVE SOMETHING TO DO WITH THE ATTACKS?
HOW DO WE THINK JACK'S GONNA LEAD US TO ASSAD?
CHLOE, I CAN'T TALK ABOUT THIS. NOT YET. WHY NOT?
CAN BILL BUCHANAN TALK ABOUT IT? HE'S MEETING JACK AT POINT MUGU NAVAL AIR STATION.
NOW OPEN THAT MILITARY CHANNEL PUT IT THROUGH TO THE CONFERENCE AREA.
THE PRESIDENT MUST HAVE GIVEN UP A LOT TO MAKE THIS HAPPEN.
I WISH HE WERE COMING BACK UNDER DIFFERENT CIRCUMSTANCES.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT HIS STATE OF MIND WILL BE.
IF HE DOESN'T COOPERATE, WE NEED TO BE PREPARED.
MISTER BUCHANAN, I NEED YOUR SIGNATURE ON THIS RELEASE DOCUMENT.
TAKE THOSE CUFFS OFF HIM.
JACK. IT'S OKAY. COME WITH ME.
PLEASE CONVEY TO YOUR PRESIDENT THAT MISTER BAUER NEVER BROKE HIS SILENCE.
HE HASN'T SPOKEN A WORD IN NEARLY TWO YEARS.
YOUR PRESIDENT HAS PAID A HIGH PRICE FOR MISTER BAUER'S FREEDOM.
WHAT HE WANTS FROM HIM MUST BE VERY IMPORTANT.
PRESIDENT PALMER WANTS TO SPEAK TO YOU HIMSELF AS SOON AS WE DEBRIEF.
I'M SORRY, JACK. HOW COULD YOU KNOW?
WAYNE PALMER IS PRESIDENT.
HE'S THE ONE WHO NEGOTIATED YOUR RELEASE.
I CAN'T EVEN BEGIN TO IMAGINE WHAT YOU WENT THROUGH OVER, JACK.
BUT THERE'S A REASON YOU'RE HERE NOW.
THE LAST ELEVEB WEEKS, OUR CITIES HAVE BEEN TARGETED BY A SERIES OF TERROR ATTACKS.
BUSES, TRAINS, SHOPPING MALLS.
THE LAST ONE WAS FIFTEEN MINUTES AGO HERE IN LOS ANGELES.
IT'S HAMRI AL-ASSAD.
ASSAD'S HERE, JACK.
FOUR DAYS AGO, ONE OF ASSAD'S MEN CONTACTED US.
HE SAID HE'D GIVE UP ASSAD FOR TWENTY FIVE MILLION DOLLARS.
BUT HE'S DEMANDING SOMETHING MORE THAN MONEY.
HE WANTS YOU, JACK.
HE WANTS YOU DEAD.
IT'S ABU FAYED.
HE WANTS HIS POUND OF FLESH FOR WHAT HAPPENED IN BEIRUT.
WE OFFERED HIM OTHER ALTERNATIVES. WE DID EVERYTHING WE COULD THINK OF, JACK.
BUT HE WOULD ONLY AGREE TO GIVE US ASSAD IN EXCHANGE FOR YOU.
HE'S DEMANDED OUR SURVEILLANCE PROTOCOLS,
WHICH MEANS WE CAN'T RISK AN EXTRACTION.
ONCE HE HAS YOU, YOU'LL BE ON YOUR OWN.
YOU UNDERSTAND WHAT THIS MEANS, JACK?
WE'RE ASKING YOU TO SACRIFICE YOURSELF,
SO WE CAN ELIMINATE ASSAD.
I CAN'T HEAR YOU, JACK.
AUDREY?
AUDREY DOESN'T KNOW YOU'RE BACK.
MY DAUGHTER?
KIM DOESN'T KNOW EITHER.
YOU KEEP IT THAT WAY.
I KNOW WHAT'S BEING ASKED OF ME, CURTIS.
YOU DON'T NEED YOUR FIREARM.
BEFORE WE DO THIS,
I WOULD LIKE TO CLEAN UP.
WE'VE GOT AN AREA SET UP FOR YOU,
AND BROUGHT YOU SOME NEW CLOTHES.
BILL?
WE HAVE JACK. GOOD.
I THOUGHT I WAS PREPARED, BUT HE'S WORSE THAN I EXPECTED. MUCH WORSE.
I KNOW HOW HARD THIS MUST BE FOR YOU,
BUT EVERYTHING DEPENDS ON THIS OPERATION.
I UNDERSTAND.
I KNOW YOU DO.
I WISH I WERE THERE WITH YOU.
YOU'RE WHERE YOU NEED TO BE.
I MISS YOU.
I MISS YOU TOO.
I HAVE TO TAKE JACK TO THE DROP POINT NOW.
BYE.
LOS ANGELES HAS NOW BEEN ADDED TO THE LIST OF MAJOR CITIES HIT BY TERRORIST ATTACKS.
THE DEPARTMENT OF HOMELAND SECURITY HAS RAISED THE THREAT LEVEL TO RED...
THE HIGHEST LEVEL SINCE THE DEPARTMENT WAS FORMED.
F.B.I. WILL HANDLE ALL THE FIELD SEARCHES OUTSIDE THE CITY,
SO JUST FOCUS ON THE MAIN GRID. YES, MA'AM.
NADIA, I NEED TO TALK TO YOU.
RIGHT. FINISH THAT UP AND CHECK BACK WITH ME. OKAY.
DID YOU OPEN THAT MILITARY CHANNEL PUT IT THROUGH TO THE CONFERENCE AREA?
YEAH. I'VE BEEN TRYING TO LOCATE BILL OR CURTIS TO FIND OUT WHAT'S GOING ON WITH JACK,
BUT THEY'RE BOTH OFF-LINE, AND THERE'S A BLOCK ON THEIR STATUS ROSTERS.
I TOLD YOU, CHLOE. I CAN'T TALK ABOUT THIS.
NADIA, YOU'VE ONLY BEEN HERE A COUPLE MONTHS, SO YOU DON'T KNOW ME VERY WELL,
BUT IF YOU DID, YOU WOULD KNOW HOW MUCH JACK BAUER MEANS TO ME.
YOU WOULD ALSO KNOW THAT SOONER OR LATER I WILL FIND OUT. SO WHY DON'T YOU JUST TELL ME RIGHT NOW?
CHLOE, I DON'T HAVE THE AUTHORIZATION...
OKAY, WHY DON'T I JUST CALL DIVISION AND LET THEM KNOW...
ABOUT THE TIME THAT YOU LEFT THE JARVIS FIREWALL UNSECURED?
IF IT WEREN'T FOR ME, YOU WOULD HAVE BEEN FIRED OVER THAT.
WE WERE CONTACTED FOUR DAYS AGO BY A MAN NAMED FAYED.
HE OFFERED TO GIVE US ASSAD'S LOCATION FOR A LIST OF DEMANDS. ONE OF THEM WAS JACK BAUER.
JACK? WHY DOES HE WANT JACK?
RETRIBUTION. RETRIBUTION FOR WHAT?
FAYED'S BROTHER WAS PART OF THE CELL THAT BOMBED OUR EMBASSY IN LEBANON IN NINETEEN NINETY NINE.
JACK WAS SENT IN TO GRAB HIM AND GET THE NAMES OF THE OTHER CELL MEMBERS.
FAYED'S BROTHER DIED WHILE JACK WAS INTERROGATING HIM.
NOW HE WANTS JACK DEAD. THAT'S RIGHT.
AND YOU'RE REALLY GONNA JUST DELIVER JACK OVER TO THE TERRORISTS TO BE KILLED?
- NADIA... - WE NEED TO STOP ASSAD.
WHY AREN'T WE ORGANIZING A RESCUE? WE CAN GRAB JACK ONCE FAYED GIVES US ASSAD'S LOCATION.
FAYED HAS THE RESOURCES TO DETECT OUR SURVEILLANCE.
AS PART OF THE DEAL, WE GAVE FAYED MONITORING ACCESS TO OUR SATELLITE COVERAGE,
RADIO FREQUENCIES AND AIR CORRIDORS.
HE WON'T GIVE US ANYTHING UNTIL HE'S FREE AND CLEAR WITH JACK.
HOW DO WE EVEN KNOW HE'LL DO WHAT HE SAYS?
WE DON'T.
I'M CALLING KAREN HAYES. SHE'LL TALK TO THE PRESIDENT.
CHLOE, DON'T YOU GET IT? KAREN ALREADY KNOWS.
SO DOES PRESIDENT PALMER. HE AUTHORIZED IT.
LOOK,
I'M SORRY ABOUT YOUR FRIEND,
BUT THERE'S NOTHING YOU, I OR ANYONE CAN DO.
RIGHT NOW, THIS IS OUR ONLY WAY OUT OF THIS CRISIS.
IF WE WANT THESE ATTACKS TO STOP, JACK BAUER HAS TO BE SACRIFICED.
I'VE ONLY GOTTEN HALF THOSE UPGRADES. YOU'LL GET THE REST IN A MINUTE.
NO, I NEED THEM NOW, MORRIS. I NEEDED THEM 10 MINUTES AGO.
AND DON'T EXPECT CHLOE TO KEEP RUNNING INTERFERENCE FOR YOU.
YOU'LL GET YOUR UPGRADES. WHEN?
WHAT'S GOING ON BETWEEN YOU AND NADIA?
THE PRESIDENT GOT JACK BACK FROM THE CHINESE.
HE'S IN L.A. NOW. WELL, THAT'S VERY GOOD NEWS.
NO, MORRIS, IT'S NOT.
BUCHANAN. BILL, IT'S THE PRESIDENT. IS JACK WITH YOU?
YES, SIR. WE'RE ALMOST TO THE DROP POINT.
LET ME SPEAK TO HIM, PLEASE.
I'LL PUT HIM ON. JACK.
JACK.
IT'S PRESIDENT PALMER. HE WANTS TO TALK TO YOU.
MISTER PRESIDENT. JACK.
I'VE BEEN TRYING TO THINK OF WHAT I COULD POSSIBLY SAY TO YOU,
AFTER ALL THAT YOU'VE SACRIFICED FOR THIS COUNTRY,
WHAT YOU'VE DONE FOR ME IN THE PAST,
AND, OF COURSE, WHAT YOU'VE DONE FOR MY BROTHER DAVID.
THIS IS A DESPERATE MEASURE, JACK. BELIEVE ME, I KNOW.
BUT IT'S ALSO A MEASURE OF OUR DESPERATION.
PEOPLE ARE AFRAID TO COME OUTSIDE.
THEY'RE AFRAID TO LEAVE THEIR HOMES, JACK.
I MEAN, THEY'RE ACTUALLY STARTING TO TURN AGAINST EACH OTHER OUT THERE.
BILL BUCHANAN EXPLAINED THE SITUATION, SIR. I KNOW WHAT'S HAPPENING.
I UNDERSTAND WHAT'S EXPECTED OF ME.
YOU HAVE MY WORD... MY WORD, JACK...
YOUR SACRIFICE WILL NOT BE IN VAIN.
THANK YOU.
GOD BLESS YOU, JACK. GOOD-BYE, MISTER PRESIDENT.
WHEN I AGREED TO RUN FOR THIS OFFICE, I THOUGHT THAT I UNDERSTOOD THIS JOB.
I MEAN, I WAS RIGHT BESIDE MY BROTHER DAVID...
WHEN HE HAD TO MAKE IMPOSSIBLE DECISIONS, YOU KNOW?
TIMES WHEN HE HAD TO CHOOSE BETWEEN BAD OPTIONS.
BUT NOW THAT I'M THE ONE SITTING IN THAT CHAIR,
I'M STARTING TO WONDER IF I'M THE RIGHT PERSON TO LEAD THIS COUNTRY.
IT'S AN IRRELEVANT QUESTION, SIR.
EXCUSE ME?
YOU WILL LEAD THIS COUNTRY,
WHETHER YOU WANT TO OR NOT.
YOU ARE THE PRESIDENT.
WELL, THIS PRESIDENT CAN'T SHAKE THE FEELING...
THAT SACRIFICING JACK BAUER IS A MISTAKE,
AND THAT MAYBE I SHOULD CALL THIS WHOLE THING OFF BEFORE IT'S TOO LATE.
NO, SIR. YOU HAVE NOT MADE A MISTAKE.
AND, FOR WHAT IT'S WORTH, YOUR BROTHER...
WOULD BE DOING JUST THE SAME THING.
THAT DOESN'T MAKE IT RIGHT.
IT ISN'T RIGHT. IT ISN'T WRONG.
IT'S SIMPLY OUR ONLY OPTION.
BAUER HAS TO BE SACRIFICED SO THIS COUNTRY CAN SURVIVE.
- I JUST HEARD A DISTURBING RUMOR. - WHAT RUMOR'S THAT?
THAT YOU'RE AUTHORIZING THE NATIONAL GUARD TO SET UP DETENTION FACILITIES...
AT CONVENTION CENTERS AND SPORTS ARENAS IN LOS ANGELES, DETROIT AND PHILADELPHIA.
YEAH, THAT... THAT'S CORRECT.
THAT'S AGAINST THE PRESIDENT'S ORDER. I WAS THERE WHEN HE GAVE IT.
KAREN, I KNOW WHERE YOU WERE. I WAS STANDING RIGHT NEXT TO YOU.
TO MY KNOWLEDGE, THAT ORDER HASN'T BEEN RESCINDED.
ALL RIGHT, YOU WERE CONFUSED.
I HAVEN'T IMPLEMENTED ANYTHING YET. I'M MERELY POSITIONING.
IF THE PRESIDENT CHANGES HIS MIND,
AS I SUSPECT HE WILL, THEN WE WILL HAVE WASTED LESS TIME.
I'M NOT CONFUSED, TOM. AND YOU CAN USE WHATEVER WORDS YOU LIKE.
IN PLAIN ENGLISH, YOU'RE SECOND-GUESSING THE PRESIDENT.
PLAIN ENGLISH DOES NOT ALLOW FOR THE NUANCES THAT MY JOB REQUIRES, KAREN.
AND JUST HOW FAR ARE YOU GONNA PUSH THIS?
THE ACLU IS ALREADY FILING COMPLAINTS...
AGAINST US THAT WE'VE GIVEN THE BUREAU TOO MUCH FIELD AUTHORITY.
AND, BY MY LIGHTS, THEY HAVE NOT BEEN GIVEN NEAR ENOUGH.
THEY NEED A WIDER NET WITH TIGHTER MESH.
AND WHAT HAPPENS WHEN INNOCENT PEOPLE GET CAUGHT IN THAT NET?
WELL, LIKE I TOLD YOU BEFORE, SECURITY HAS ITS PRICE.
JUST GET USED TO IT, KAREN.
GO AHEAD.
SECURE BAUER'S WRIST TO THE GRATE. THEN LEAVE HIM THERE.
FIRST TELL ME WHERE ASSAD IS.
THIS ISN'T A NEGOTIATION.
IF YOU WANT ASSAD, LEAVE BAUER HERE,
GET BACK IN YOUR CAR AND DRIVE AWAY.
I'M WATCHING YOU.
YOU LISTEN TO ME, YOU SON OF A BITCH.
HE WANTS ME TO HANDCUFF YOU TO THAT GRATE.
DO IT.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO SAY, JACK.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN DYING FOR SOMETHING AND DYING FOR NOTHING?
THE ONLY REASON I FOUGHT SO HARD TO STAY ALIVE IN CHINA...
WAS BECAUSE I DIDN'T WANT TO DIE FOR NOTHING.
AND TODAY...
I CAN DIE FOR SOMETHING.
MY WAY, MY CHOICE.
TO BE HONEST WITH YOU, IT'LL BE A RELIEF.
I'M SORRY, JACK. DON'T BE.
BILL, YOU NEED TO GO.
GO.
FIREMEN ARE BATTLING A FIRE AT THE AL-HAMZA MOSQUE IN CULVER CITY.
MEMBERS OF THE MOSQUE ARE CALLING THE INCIDENT...
A RETALIATION FOR THIS MORNING'S SUICIDE BOMBING...
THAT HAPPENED DOWNTOWN ON A METRO BUS.
SCOTT SHOULDN'T BE GOIN' TO SCHOOL. HE HAS A GEOMETRY TEST.
HONEY, L.A. WAS JUST HIT. I MEAN, THEY SHOULD BE CLOSING THESE SCHOOLS DOWN.
THEY WILL CLOSE THEM DOWN WHEN IT'S NOT SAFE.
BUT UNTIL THEN, I DON'T WANNA SCARE OUR SON,
AND I DON'T WANT YOU SCARING HIM EITHER.
I WANT US TO KEEP LIVING OUR LIVES AS NORMALLY AS WE CAN.
LOOK, JILLIAN, THERE IS NOTHING NORMAL, WHAT'S HAPPENING HERE.
WELL, WHAT ARE WE SUPPOSED TO DO?
- JUST HIDE INSIDE OUR HOUSE FOR THE REST OF OUR LIVES? - NO, IT'S SHOU...
HEY. WAS AHMED ABLE TO HELP?
I DIDN'T GET A CHANCE TO SEE HIM. THE F.B.I. ARE AT HIS HOUSE.
THEY'RE ARRESTING HIS DAD. WHAT?
- WHY ARE THEY TAKING HIM? - I DON'T KNOW.
THIS IS INSANE! YOU CAN'T ARREST SOMEBODY WITHOUT A REASON.
HE'S NOT A TERRORIST!
HE'S INNOCENT!
THERE'S GOTTA BE SOME REASON. I'M SURE IT'S A MISTAKE.
AHMED! WHAT ARE YOU DOIN'?
WE JUST WANNA TALK TO YOU, OKAY?
AHMED, GET OUT HERE!
IT'S THAT GUY DOWN THE BLOCK. THAT CONTRACTOR... STAN SOMETHING.
YEAH, I KNOW. I'LL CALL THE POLICE. COME ON!
WHY DON'T YOU GET THE HELL OUT OF MY NEIGHBORHOOD!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING? I'M HELPING AHMED.
YOUR FATHER IS CALLING THE POLICE.
- THEY WON'T DO ANYTHING. - SCOTT, STOP. YOU'RE NOT GOING OVER THERE.
DAD, I'M NOT HIDING HERE WHILE AHMED GETS BEAT UP,
- 'CAUSE YOU'RE SCARED TO DO THE RIGHT THING. - SCOTT, STAY HERE.
I'LL HANDLE IT.
HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY. I I JUST WANNA TALK TO YOU.
- GET OUT OF MY HOUSE. - WE'RE JUST HERE TO GIVE YOU A LITTLE FRIENDLY ADVICE, OKAY?
STAN! STAN! WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU DOIN', MAN?
I'M TRYIN' TO PROTECT MY FAMILY, RAY.
THIS KID'S FATHER'S A TERRORIST.
OH, COME ON. HE'S NO MORE OF A TERRORIST THAN YOU OR ME. YEAH?
THEN WHY'D THEY ARREST HIM? BECAUSE THEY'RE SCARED, LIKE EVERYONE ELSE.
AW, GET OUT OF MY WAY. HEY, STAN, COME ON! STAN.
WHAT? IF YOU WANT HIM, YOU'RE COMING THROUGH ME.
THIS ISN'T OVER, RAY.
YOU ALL RIGHT? YEAH.
ALL RIGHT, LOOK, UM, I... I THINK WHAT WE SHOULD DO IS, YOU SHOULD COME STAY WITH US...
UNTIL THINGS GET SORTED OUT WITH YOUR FATHER.
LOOK, I APPRECIATE WHAT YOU JUST DID, BUT I'LL BE FINE.
LOOK, THIS GUY... THIS GUY IS A JERK. I DON'T WANT YOU STAYING HERE ALONE. IT'S DANGEROUS.
I'M NOT TAKING NO FOR AN ANSWER. YOU'RE COMING WITH ME.
NADIA. BILL BUCHANAN FOR YOU. RIGHT.
- BILL. - JACK'S AT THE DROP POINT. ARE WE SET WITH THE MILITARY?
THE MARINES HAVE TWO COBRA ATTACK HELICOPTERS READY TO DEPLOY.
WE CAN HIT ANY TARGET INSIDE L.A. WITHIN TWENTY MINUTES.
JACK'S GIVING HIS LIFE FOR THIS OPERATION,
SO I DON'T WANT ANY MISTAKES.
ASSAD MUST BE TAKEN OUT WITH EXTREME PREJUDICE.
HE WILL BE, SIR, JUST AS SOON AS WE GET HIS LOCATION FROM FAYED.
IF FAYED CALLS BEFORE I GET BACK, LOOP ME IN. OKAY.
BILL. YEAH?
- I'M SIDELINING CHLOE ON THIS OPERATION. - WHY?
SHE STARTED ASKING QUESTIONS ABOUT JACK.
I... I TRIED PUTTING HER OFF, BUT I...
WHAT DID YOU TELL HER? THE TRUTH.
- I'LL TALK TO HER WHEN I GET THERE. - THANKS.
MOVE OVER. WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'M GONNA TRY AND GET A VISUAL ON JACK.
I TOLD YOU, FAYED HAS OUR SURVEILLANCE PROTOCOLS.
HE'S MONITORING FULL-SPECTRUM RADIO, SATELLITE ORBITS AND TRANSMISSIONS.
I HAVE ACCESS TO A SATELLITE THAT'S OFF THE GOVERNMENT GRID.
HOW? I DID A DROP OF WORK FOR THIS ENERGY CONSORTIUM IN UZBEKISTAN.
THEY NEEDED AN ILLEGAL AERIAL SURVEY OF SOME OIL FIELDS. I NEEDED SOME QUICK CASH.
AHA, LOOK.
THE LITTLE BIRD... SHE'S STILL FLYING. SHE'S STILL FLYING.
I THINK I CAN REPOSITION THE CAMERA FROM HERE. MORRIS.
AH, DON'T THANK ME YET, LOVE.
JUST STOP SULKING, AND FIND OUT WHERE BILL BUCHANAN LEFT JACK.
I'VE BEEN WAITING FOR THIS FOR A LONG TIME.
- YES. - THERE IS A PROBLEM. DON'T MOVE OUT OF THE TUNNEL YET.
- WHAT? - I JUST INTERCEPTED A SIGNAL TO A PRIVATELY OWNED SATELLITE.
THERE ARE HUNDREDS OF PRIVATE SATELLITES.
THE SIGNAL IS BEING TRANSMITTED ON A GOVERNMENT FREQUENCY.
THIS SATELLITE... WHAT'S IT LOOKING AT? I CAN'T PINPOINT IT,
BUT THE CAMERA'S BEEN REPOSITIONED TO YOUR SECTOR.
CONNECT ME TO C.T.U.
CHLOE, THIS IS IT. THIS IS IT.
AS SOON AS THE MILITARY HAS ASSAD'S LOCATION,
WE'LL WORK WITH LOCAL LAW ENFORCEMENT TO LIMIT COLLATERAL DAMAGE.
AS MUCH AS WE'RE TRYING TO PREVENT CIVILIAN LOSSES,
OUR PRIORITY IS TO TAKE OUT ASSAD.
FAYED IS ON THE LINE.
THIS IS NADIA YASSIR.
REDIRECT THE SATELLITE YOU HAVE AIMED AT THIS SECTOR.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
THEN EXPLAIN THE ACTIVITY ON FREQUENCY ALPHA-0703.
BAUER IS DEAD EITHER WAY,
BUT IF YOU DON'T REDIRECT THAT SATELLITE IN 30 SECONDS, YOU WILL LOSE ASSAD.
I'M TELLING YOU, THERE'S NO SATELLITE. TWENTY-EIGHT SECONDS.
NADIA.
WHERE IS THIS COMING FROM?
INSIDE THE BUILDING. WHERE?
CHLOE'S STATION.
MORRIS. WHAT, LOVE?
REDIRECT THAT SATELLITE.
- REDIRECT THAT SATELLITE. - THE SITUATION IS UNDER CONTROL.
NO, FAYED TAGGED YOUR TRANSMISSION.
WE MAY HAVE LOST OUR ONLY CHANCE AT LOCATING ASSAD.
FAYED, THIS WAS A ROGUE OPERATION. WE'RE REDIRECTING THE SATELLITE NOW.
YOU HAVE 10 SECONDS. MORRIS, DO IT!
NINE. EIGHT. COME ON!
HURRY UP. I'M GOING AS FAST AS I CAN.
SEVEN. SIX. FIVE. FOUR.
IT'S DONE.
IT'S MOVING AWAY, FAYED. THEY REDIRECTED THE SATELLITE.
OTHER CHANNELS? ALL CLEAR.
BECAUSE OF YOUR DECEPTION,
I WILL HAVE TO THINK ABOUT GIVING YOU ASSAD'S LOCATION.
BUT WHAT ABOUT OUR DEAL?
FAYED?
- WE MAY HAVE SPOOKED FAYED. - I HEARD WHAT HAPPENED!
DAMN IT!
WHAT WERE YOU THINKING? IT'S MY FAULT. YOU CAN FIRE ME.
I'D FIRE BOTH OF YOU RIGHT NOW, BUT I CAN'T AFFORD TO LOSE THE MANPOWER. CHLOE.
LOOK AT ME. I'D RATHER NOT, SIR.
LOOK AT ME.
DON'T THINK YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE MOURNING JACK. YOU'RE NOT.
THAT MAY HAVE BEEN OUR ONLY OPTION.
YOU BOTH BETTER HOPE TO GOD YOU DIDN'T JUST BLOW IT.
WE MAY HAVE SACRIFICED JACK FOR NOTHING.
BUCHANAN. BILL, HAVE YOU HEARD FROM FAYED?
- NOT YET. NO. - THE PRESIDENT'S WORRIED.
FAYED SHOULD HAVE CONTACTED US BY NOW.
THERE MAY BE A PROBLEM. THERE'S A POSSIBILITY FAYED'S GOING BACK ON THE DEAL.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT? HE CAUGHT US TRYING TO TRACK JACK.
THE ORDERS WERE THAT HE WAS TO HAVE A CLEAR FIELD.
I KNOW WHAT THE ORDERS WERE. CHLOE THOUGHT THERE WAS A WORK-AROUND.
SHE DID IT WITHOUT AUTHORIZATION. AW, DAMN IT, BILL!
SHE'S YOUR RESPONSIBILITY. HOW COULD YOU LET THIS HAPPEN? IF WE DON'T TAKE OUT ASSAD...
I DON'T NEED A LECTURE, KAREN. I KNOW WHAT THE STAKES ARE. I DON'T THINK YOU DO.
IF THESE ATTACKS DON'T STOP, THERE ARE PEOPLE IN THIS ADMINISTRATION...
WHO ARE WILLING TO TEAR UP THE CONSTITUTION IN THE NAME OF NATIONAL SECURITY.
THE THINGS THEY'RE TALKING ABOUT DOING...
THIS COUNTRY WILL NEVER RECOVER.
AS SOON AS I HEAR FROM FAYED, YOU'LL BE MY FIRST CALL.
I'M SORRY, BILL. IT'S JUST, I'M...
THERE'S NO NEED TO APOLOGIZE. WE'RE ALL FEELING IT.
I HAVE TO GO.
ANYTHING? IT'S CLEAR.
- ARE YOU SURE? - YES. THEY'RE LEAVING US ALONE.
THE MONEY'S BEEN TRANSFERRED. SHOULD WE CALL C.T.U.?
NOT YET.
YOU NEED TO CALL C.T.U.
I WON'T LET YOU DIE UNTIL I'M READY.
THE CHINESE DIDN'T LEAVE MUCH FOR ME TO WORK WITH.
BUT BEFORE YOU DIE, YOU'RE GOING TO FEEL WHAT MY BROTHER FELT.
I SAW HIS BODY. I KNOW HOW HE DIED.
I KNOW WHAT YOU DID TO HIM.
YOU DON'T NEED ME TO TELL YOU...
THAT THE NERVES ARE BUNDLED HERE.
BETTER.
YOU NEED TO GIVE C.T.U. ASSAD'S LOCATION.
THAT WAS THE DEAL.
ASSAD HAS LOST FAITH IN OUR FIGHT.
HE THINKS OUR TACTICS ARE FAILING.
HE'S BEGUN TALKING ABOUT COMPROMISE,
ABOUT LAYING DOWN OUR ARMS AND NEGOTIATING.
BUT THERE'S NO COMPROMISE, NO NEGOTIATION.
ASSAD IS A TRAITOR.
AND SOON, INSHALLAH,
HE WILL BE DEAD.
THAT'S RIGHT, JACK.
C.T.U. IS ABOUT TO KILL THE WRONG MAN.
ASSAD ISN'T BEHIND THESE ATTACKS.
HE'S COME HERE TO STOP THEM.
HE'S COME HERE TO STOP ME.
YOU WILL DIE FOR NOTHING.
IF FAYED DOESN'T CALL IN FIVE MINUTES, REASSIGN EVERYONE HERE.
IT'S HIM. THIS IS BUCHANAN.
YOU KEPT YOUR END OF THE DEAL. I'LL KEEP MINE.
I'M LISTENING. I HAVE A TRANSPONDER AT ASSAD'S LOCATION.
THIRTY-THREE, 58, 11, NORTH LATITUDE.
THIRTY-THREE, 58, 11.
118, 21, 40, WEST LONGITUDE.
YOU'LL FIND ASSAD THERE.
- WHERE IS THAT? - IT'S COMING.
INGLEWOOD.
HAVE GENERAL BOWEN MOBILIZE THE ATTACK HELICOPTERS. I'LL LET THE PRESIDENT KNOW WE'RE A GO.
CUT OFF FAYED'S ACCESS TO ALL OUR SURVEILLANCE.
I WANNA LOCK DOWN ALL OF OUR SATELLITES. SHUT 'EM DOWN. YOU GOT IT?
WE DID EVERYTHING WE COULD.
I KNOW IT'S TRULY AWFUL, BUT IF IT STOPS THESE ATTACKS,
IT'S FOR THE GREATER GOOD.
THERE'S NO ONE THAT UNDERSTANDS THAT MORE THAN JACK.
DO YOU REMEMBER DOING THIS TO MY BROTHER?
FAYED? WHAT IS IT?
THERE IS A CALL FOR YOU. IT'S IMPORTANT.
YES. THERE'S A PROBLEM.
TELL ME WHAT HAPPENED.
- THE F.B.I... THEY TOOK MY FATHER. - WHERE ARE YOU?
I'M AT A NEIGHBOR'S.
FAYED, YOU KNOW MY FATHER'S INNOCENT.
HE HAS NO IDEA WHAT WE'RE DOING.
IF YOUR FATHER IS MEANT TO BE SACRIFICED,
THAT IS HOW IT WILL BE.
NOW TELL ME WHAT THE F.B.I. SAID.
GOOD. YOU DID THE RIGHT THING.
ARE YOU SURE THE F.B.I. DIDN'T FIND THE PACKAGE?
YES, IT'S WELL HIDDEN.
YOU NEED TO DELIVER IT SOON. I'LL CALL YOU WHEN I HAVE IT.
EVERYTHING OKAY? YEAH, IT WAS JUST MY UNCLE.
HE'S TRYING TO FIND OUT WHERE THEY TOOK MY DAD.
WANNA COME EAT? YEAH.
GET IN THERE!
FIND HIM!